RAJAT

(Android Developer)

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Qtr 764-C, Rail Coach Factory, Kapurthala, Punjab, (144602) India

PHONE

+91 78371-07577

EMAIL

rajatkalia13@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH

13-11-1993

NATIONALITY

INDIAN

LINKS

LinkedIn

Bitbucket

<u>Github</u>

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Problem Solving, Leadership

Language: JAVA

Tools: Android Studio, Postman

Others: GIT, Bitbucket

OS: Android, MAC, Ubuntu

PROFILE

Strong knowledge of Android SDK, different versions of Android, and how to deal with different screen sizes. Proficient in working with RESTful APIs to connect Android applications to back-end services. Worked on FinTech models like Payment gateways, UPI, digital wallets, Mobile banking (DMT), BBPS, AEPS, M-ATM, Recharges etc.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sr. Android Developer, Parnav Online Solution Pvt. Ltd

Ghaziabad, IN

Noida, IN

Feb 2022 — Present

Parnav Online Solutions serves as a companion to facilitate various online services backed by trusted servers and qualified team. In this company I am working on 3 projects.

- working on WellProCare app, PayIMPS, CityRecharge
- · Integrated SDK's like Bankit, Paytm, Fingpay, Credopay etc.
- Working on UPI, Mobile Banking, Digital wallets, AEPS, Recharge, BBPS, M-ATM services etc.

Android developer, (Aksom Enterprises) Ghaziabad, IN

Feb 2020 — Jan 2022

In this company, I have worked on 7 projects

- Worked on JVM Pay, Bharatm Pay, Sidhmoney, Payesmoney, Bingo Restaurant, QCAV apps from Scratch.
- · Worked on location, notification, fingerprint etc.
- · Integrated Bankit SDK.
- · Also work on (AES 256, MD5) for security purpose.
- · Worked on Recharge, AEPS, BBPS, DMT and UPI payment.

Android developer, (Vgamaa Services Private limited)

May 2019 — Feb 2020

Vgamaa is a Software company deals with websites and Mobile Applications.

- · Made the complete project
- · Debugging and testing
- · Reduce the size of application by 40%

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

- · Integrate Social logins(Facebook, Google)
- · Version control.

Jr. Android Developer, (Champcash)

Karnal, IN

Aug 2016 — Jun 2018

Champcash is a Affiliate marketing company which are paying money of advertisement to the user's in the form of chain system

Responsibilities:

- · Make Sasta Recharge app
- · Create the Ticketing module.
- · Make the design of the ChampCash.
- · Integrate the sdk of Leadbolt, Adcolony.

INTERNSHIPS

Intern, (APK Global pvt ltd)

Noida, IN

Mar 2016 — Jun 2016

- Served as a dedicated and supportive Intern in a fast-paced environment.
- Developed the basic Application for school attendance via QR code

PROJECTS

1. Cityrecharge & DMT (APP)

Feb 2020 — Present

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.uva.pay

2. JVM Pay

Oct 2021 — Present

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.jvm.pay

3. WellPro Care

Feb 2022 — Present

A QR Scanner App for checking the originality of product.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aksom.qrcodescanner&hl=en&g

4. SidhMoney

Aug 2020 — Jan 2022

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sid.money

5. Payesmoney

Mar 2020 — Jan 2021

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aksomtechnology.payesmoney

6. Champcash - Digital India App to Earn,Learn and Fun

7. Fast Maxi Sydney

8. Bingo Restaurant (Kurukshetra)

May 2021 — May 2021

9. BharatMPay

Jan 2022 — Present

EDUCATION

B.Tech (IT), MIMIT College (76.4 %)

Malout

Jul 2012 — Jun 2016

TRAINING

Android Course, Aptron Institute, Noida

Jan 2016 — Jun 2020

Java (J2EE), Cetpa Infotech, Noida

May 2015 — Jun 2015

NNSC workshop, Network bulls, Gurgaon

May 2014 — May 2014

EXTRA

Research Paper (2014)

Malout

 Virtual Reality as the Landmark Application of Artificial Intelligence.

CCNA Workshop

Malout

Webcasting in Punjab Loksabha Election

(2014)